africafreak.com 2019-10-28

# Privacy Policy - Africa Freak

We use Ezoic to provide personalization and analytic services on this website, as such Ezoic's privacy policy is in effect and can be reviewed [here](https://g.ezoic.net/privacy/africafreak.com).  

Your privacy is very important to us. This privacy policy explains how the information you share with us is used.

## KIND OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT

If you choose to register on our site, we ask you for information such as name, e-mail address, postal address, age, gender, or telephone number. We may track certain information about you based upon your behavior on our site. We use this information to do internal research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand, protect and serve our users. This information is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis.

## USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We use the information we receive about you in connection with the services and features we provide to you and other users like your friends, the advertisers that purchase ads on the site, and the developers who build the games, applications, and websites you use.

• We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our services, or protect our rights.  
• We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our services.  
• We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private.

We may use the information we receive about you:

• as part of our efforts to keep our Site safe and secure;  
• to provide you with location features and services, like telling you and your friends when something is going on nearby;  
• to measure or understand the effectiveness of ads you and others see;  
• to make suggestions to you and other users on our Site.

Granting us this permission not only allows us to provide AfricaFreak.com as it exists today, but it also allows us to provide you with innovative features and services we develop in the future that use the information we receive about you in new ways.

While you are allowing us to use the information we receive about you, you always own all of your information. Your trust is important to us, which is why we don’t share information we receive about you with others unless we have:

• received your permission;  
• given you notice, such as by telling you about it in this policy; or  
• removed your name or any other personally identifying information from it.

## THIRD PARTY LINKS

The service may contain links to third party websites that are not owned or controlled by us. AfricaFreak.com has no control over, and assumes no responsibility for, the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third party websites. In addition, we will not and cannot censor or edit the content of any third-party site. By using the service, you expressly relieve AfricaFreak.com from any and all liability arising from your use of any third-party website.

Accordingly, we encourage you to be aware when you leave the service and to read the terms and conditions and privacy policy of each other website that you visit.

## AFFILIATION

As an Amazon Associate we earn from qualifying purchases.

We may also receive commissions for other activities related to affiliate marketing.

## USE OF COOKIES

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. We use cookies to help AfricaFreak.com identify and track visitors, their usage of our Site, and their Site access preferences. AfricaFreak.com users who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using our Sites, with the drawback that certain features of our Sites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

## COMMENTS

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

## MEDIA

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

## EMBEDDED CONTENT FROM OTHER WEBSITES

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

## HOW LONG WE RETAIN YOUR DATA

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## WHAT RIGHTS YOU HAVE OVER YOUR DATA

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## WHERE WE SEND YOUR DATA

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES

Although most changes are likely to be minor, AfricaFreak.com may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in AfricaFreak.com’s sole discretion. AfricaFreak.com encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

**Last Updated on October 22, 2019**
